# Asher Shaheen

linkedin.com/in/asher-shaheen



646-342-5919 (NYC)



github.com/Asher978



ashershaheen@gmail.com



asher.io



#### CAREER OVERVIEW

A committed, innovative and fast-learning Full Stack
Web Developer with an extensive experience in
leadership and a passion for providing solutions and
enhancing customer experience. My 15+
experience in meeting and exceeding business/
customer service goals lead me to find my new
passion for web development where I deliver clean
and responsive web applications. Passion for
working with others and work well under pressure.

# **CORE COMPETENCIES**

JAVASCRIPT
REACT
EXPRESS
NODE
JQUERY
RUBY ON RAILS
SINATRA
CSS 3
HTML
GIT
PSQL / POSTGRES
FIREBASE / SOCKET.IO

#### **EDUCATION & TRAINING**

### General Assembly - New York, NY

WDI - Web Development Immerse Certificate of Completion

### Queensborough Community College - NY

Associates Degree - Computer Science

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# General Assembly - New York, NY

June-2017 - Sep 2017

Web Development Immersive Student

- Tic Tac Toe: Web Game inspired by Vanilla JS (bitballoon.com/sites/magistrate-peggy-55571) - JS, HTML, CSS
- Ping Pong: Web Game inspired by Collision Detections using Jquery (asher978.github.io/Project-1-GA) - Jquery, HTML, CSS
- App On My Feet: Full Stack Web App Runner's Data Management (peaceful-waters-85500.herokuapp.com/) - JS, PSQL, Express/Node, EJS
- Code Share: Full Stack Web App Bringing individuals together and code (mysterious-anchorage-20913.herokuapp.com/) - React, socket.io, PSQL, Node
- Photographer's Professional Site Photographer's Dream come true (https://ericsapp.herokuapp.com/) React, Ruby on Rails, Firebase, JS

### Armani Exchange | Long Island Area | NY March 2012 - Feb 2015

Area Sales Manager

- Growth of 7% increase in sales volume resulting in \$58 million for the Fiscal year 2014
- Led 4 stores within the NYC metro area which included over 200 employees.
- Restructured teams based on talent to allow managers to be more effective at servicing clients.
- Developed and implemented a brand new sales training course resulting in internal growth of managers.

# **Armani Exchange** | 5<sup>th</sup> Ave Flagship | NYC April 2011 - March 2012

General Sales Manager

- Led a team of 2 Store managers, 15 Co managers and over 200 sales / stock associates through the most successful Holiday season ending the year as #1 volume in the company.
- Controlled payroll by creating weekly budgets for all departments and following up daily to maximize productivity.
- Performed weekly management meetings, challenged product placement to maximize sales and people development within the leadership team.
- Pioneered new company initiative KRONOS and provided peer support amongst other stores.

# Armani Exchange | Queens Center Mall | NY September 2005 - March 2011

Store Sales Manager

- Actively reacted and captured opportunities to maximize sales.
   Increased and maximized profitability from \$5 million to \$9 million within 2 years.
- Pioneered extended hours for Holiday 2008 to maximize sales, thus resulting in 30% comp sales for the 4th Quarter.
- Developed and trained a strong sales team through providing mentorship and feedback on sales strategies.